## Shilpa Saini

Software Engineer at Apple

## Summary

Current - Software Engineer at Apple

Software Engineering graduate student from San Jose State University. I have more than 3 years of work experience in IT industry where i demonstrated problem solving skills,team work, strong communication and interpersonal competencies.

As an IT professional, I performed a mix of responsibilities, learning the operations and processes of a worldclass Agile development environment. I have worked on Oracle Identity Management which is Identity Management solution for enterprise software companies.

During this period I got exposure to Oracle Identity Analytics (OIA) and Oracle Access Manager (OAM) and Oracle Identity Federation (OIF). I have extensive hands-on experience in installation, upgrading and implementation of OIA, OAM and OIF. I have rich experience in implementation of enterprise Single Sign-On and federated Single Sign-On solution.

#### **Technical Skills:**

- Programming Languages: Java, Node.js
- •Database: Oracle 11g, Mongo DB, MYSQL.
- •Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, Unix
- Development Tools: Eclipse, IntelliJ, Greenfoot, BlueJ
- •Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, ReSTFul Web Services, D3.js, High Charts.
- •Big Data: Hadoop, HDFS, Hive, Pig
- •Cloud Platforms: Pivotal Web Services, Cloud9, OpenShift, Amazon Web Services
- •Web App Servers: Apache web server, Oracle HTTP Server, Oracle Weblogic App Server.
- •Tools: VMWare ESXi, vSphere, vClient, Salesforce, Selenium, Neoload, Perfecto mobile, Elementool, Bugzilla, Appium, SVN, Github, Jira, MS project, Astah Professional, iReport, Toad, BurpSuite, App Scan.

## Experience

### **Software Engineer at Apple**

February 2016 - Present

Software Engineer in WWDR team.

#### **Cloud Engineer Intern at IBM**

#### June 2015 - December 2015 (7 months)

- •Working as part of Cloud Data Service and Reliability team of Bluemix, the IBM Cloud Platform.
- •Discovering security vulnerabilities in cloud applications and services, automating security scanning process.
- •Developing business, social and IoT application using the Bluemix services and technologies like Nodered, dashDB, SQL.
- •Working on cloud deployment tool for automating application deployment through environments.
- •Monitoring the Cloud Data Services to continuously improve service delivery and operations of the IBM Bluemix cloud.

#### Software Test Engineer Intern at ServiceNow – The Enterprise Cloud Company

March 2015 - May 2015 (3 months)

- •Developed a framework using Selenium framework, Java Reflection API and Java to automate the smoke testing of UI.
- •Used Keyword & Data Driven testing methods to automate UI testing irrespective of the customer customization, making the framework very flexible to use.

#### **Senior Software Engineer at Infosys**

October 2010 - December 2013 (3 years 3 months)

- -Installation and Deployment of Oracle Access Manager and Oracle Identity Federation 11gR1 for SSO setup in cluster.
- -Used Kerberos/WNA as authentication Scheme.
- -OIF was used for SMAL integration of external/federated applications.
- -Installation of 11g Webgates over OHS for authentication request interception.
- -Governed the access of more than 10k user on 300 plus applications by creating certifications on quarterly basis to review their access.

#### Education

#### San Jose State University

Master's degree, Computer Software Engineering, 2014 - 2015

**Activities and Societies:** International Student Organization, SJSU Bridges, Society of Computer Engineering **Punjab Technical University** 

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Electronics and Communications Engineering, 2006 - 2010

# Shilpa Saini

Software Engineer at Apple



Contact Shilpa on LinkedIn